const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",t=200,i=120,a=[{id:210,question:"When sulphur (IV) oxide is passed into a solution of sodium hydroxide for a long time. It eventually produces a solution of",option:{a:"Na2SO4",b:"NaHSO4",c:"Na2SO3",d:"NaHSO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:144,question:"Which of the following acts as both a reducing and an oxidizing agent",option:{a:"H2",b:"SO2",c:"H2S",d:"CO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:18,question:"P(g) + O(g)    ⇌ 3R(s)  +  S(g)   ΔH is negative which of the following will increase the yield of R",option:{a:"Using a larger closed vessel",b:"Increasing the temperature",c:"Removing some S",d:"Adding a positive catalyst"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:220,question:"Trioxonitrate(V) acid is not used for preparing hydrogen gas from metals because it",option:{a:"Renders the metal passive",b:"Is strongly oxidizing",c:"Is volatile",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:253,question:"The sulphide which is insoluble in dilute hydrochloric acid is",option:{a:"CuS",b:"Na2S",c:"FeS",d:"ZnS"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:278,question:"The colour of methyl orange in alkaline medium is",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Orange",c:"Red",d:"Yellow"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:288,question:"To a solution of an unknown compound, a little dilute Tetraoxosulphate (IV) acid was added with some freshly prepared (II) Tetraoxosulphate (VI) Solution. The brown ring observed after the addition of a stream of concentrated  Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid confirmed the presence of",option:{a:"CI",b:"SO",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:82,question:"According to the kinetic theory, an increase in temperature causes the kinetic energy of particles to",option:{a:"Decrease",b:"Increase",c:"Remain constant",d:"Be zero"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:270,question:"A noble gas with a high power of fog penetration used in aerodrome beacons is",option:{a:"Argon",b:"Helium",c:"Neon",d:"Krypton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:81,question:"The noble gases owe their inactivity to",option:{a:"Octet configuration",b:"Cyclic shape",c:"Hexagonal shape",d:"Obtuse configuration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:209,question:"Phenolphthalein in acidic solution is",option:{a:"Colourless",b:"Yellow",c:"Red",d:"Orange"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:114,question:"How many isomers does pentane have",option:{a:"6",b:"5",c:"4",d:"3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:196,question:"In the purification of impure samples of ethyl ethanoate synthesized by esterification, concentrated sodium trioxocarbonate(IV) solution is used to remove",option:{a:"Water",b:"Acidic impurities",c:"Basic impurities",d:"Ethoxyethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:218,question:"The ion that can be used as an oxidizing agent is",option:{a:"Fe3+",b:"F-",c:"Ca2+",d:"Au3+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:85,question:"When cathode rays are detected onto the electrode of an electrometer, the instrument becomes",option:{a:"Negatively charged",b:"Positively charged",c:"Neutral",d:"Bipolar"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:37,question:"Proteins in acid solution undergo",option:{a:"Polymerization",b:"Substitution",c:"Fermentation",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:294,question:"The residual solids from the fractional distillation of petroleum are used as",option:{a:"Raw materials for the cracking process",b:"Fuel for driving tractors",c:"Fuel for jet engines",d:"Coatings for pipes"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:83,question:` I.  H = 1s1
II. O = 1s22s22p4
III. N = 1s22s22p3
IV. Zn = 1s22s22p63s23p64s23d10
From the above, which of the following pairs is likely to be paramagnetic?
`,option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and  III",c:"I    and IV",d:"III  and IV"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:105,question:"Metals of the first transition series have special proper ties which are different from those of groups I and II elements because they have partially filled",option:{a:"s  orbitals",b:"p orbitals",c:"d orbitals",d:"f orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:186,question:"Treatment of cancer   II. Detection of leakages in water mains   III. Detection of the ages of ancient tools    Which combination of the above refers to the uses of radioactive isotopes?",option:{a:"I, II and III",b:"I, II, III and IV",c:"II and III",d:"I and II"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:90,question:"A liquid that will dissolve fast is",option:{a:"Hydrochloric acid",b:"Calcium hydroxide",c:"Kerosene",d:"Water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:230,question:"2C2H2(g)  +  5O2(g)     4CO2(g)  +  2H2O(g) In the reaction, the mass of carbon (IV) oxide produced on burning 78g of ethyne is [C = 12, O = 16, H = 1]",option:{a:"39",b:"352g",c:"264g",d:"156g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:155,question:"Carbon is tetravalent because",option:{a:"The electrons in both the 2s and 2p orbitals are equivalent",b:"The electrons in all the orbitals of carbon are equivalent",c:"The 2s and 2p atomic orbitals hybridize",d:"All the atomic orbitals of carbon hybridize"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:237,question:"Which of the following has an isomer",option:{a:"C4H10",b:"C6H6",c:"C2H4",d:"C2H6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:170,question:"The property used in the industrial preparation of nitrogen and oxygen from air is",option:{a:"Rate of diffusion",b:"Solubility",c:"Density",d:"Boiling point"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:181,question:"The most abundant element on the earth’s crust is",option:{a:"Oxygen",b:"Fluorine",c:"hydrogen",d:"nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:67,question:"Ordinary glass is manufactured from silica, Ca CO3 and",option:{a:"K2CO3",b:"NaHCO3",c:"Na2CO3",d:"K2SO4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:271,question:"Permanent hardness of water can be removed by",option:{a:"Adding slaked lime",b:"Adding caustic soda",c:"Boiling",d:"Filtration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:158,question:"Transition metals posses variable oxidation states because they have",option:{a:"Electrons in the d orbitals",b:"Electrons in the s orbitals",c:"A variable number of electrons in the p orbitals",d:"Partially filled p orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:141,question:"What volume of 0.5mol dm-3 H2SO4 will exactly neutralize 20cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH solution",option:{a:"2.0cm3",b:"5.0cm3",c:"6.8cm3",d:"8.3cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:66,question:"The postulate of Dalton’s atomic theory which still holds is that",option:{a:"Particles of different elements combine in a simple whole number ratio",b:"Atoms can neither be created nor destroyed",c:"The particles of the same element are exactly alike",d:"All elements are made of small indivisible particles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:228,question:"The volume of 2.5 moles of oxygen at s.t.p is",option:{a:"56.0dm3",b:"84.0dm3",c:"50.0dm3",d:"20.0dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:212,question:"What will happen if an aluminum spoon is used to stir a solution of iron (II) trioxonitrate(V)",option:{a:"The spoon will be reduced while the iron(II) ions will be oxidized",b:"The spoon will be oxidized while the iron (II) ions will be reduced to the metal",c:"The spoon will be reduced",d:"The spoon will increase in size"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:282,question:"Iron can be protected from corrosion by coating the surface with",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Gold"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:108,question:"The salt that will form a precipitate soluble in excess ammonia solution is",option:{a:"Ca(NO3)2",b:"Cu(NO3)2",c:"Mg(NO3)2",d:"Al(NO3)3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:213,question:"Which of the following equimolar solutions will have the highest pH",option:{a:"NH4OH",b:"CH3COONa",c:"HCI",d:"NaOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:7,question:"Four elements W, X, Y, and Z have atomic numbers 2, 6, 16 and 20 respectively. Which of these elements is a metal",option:{a:"X",b:"W",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:242,question:"The gas obtained as a product of anaerobic action ob organic matter buried in the earth is",option:{a:"Nitrogen(IV) oxide",b:"Carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Methane",d:"Ethene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:216,question:"H2(g)  +  Br2(g) →  2BHr(g)  The reaction above is carried out at 250C. If Δ H is kJ mol-1 and   Δ S is -106J mol-1K-1 the reaction will",option:{a:"Proceed spontaneously at lower temperatures",b:"Not proceed spontaneously at the given temperature",c:"Proceed spontaneously at the given temperature",d:"[proceed in the reverse direction at the given temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:24,question:" 2SO2(g) + O2(g) ⇌  2SO3(g)  The equilibrium constant for the reaction above is increased by  [ΔH = -189kJ mol -1]",option:{a:"Increasing the temperature of the system",b:"Increasing the pressure of the system",c:"The addition of a catalyst to the system",d:"Increasing the surface area of the vessel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:52,question:"The substance least considered as a source of environmental pollution is",option:{a:"Silicate minerals",b:"Uranium",c:"Lead compounds",d:"Organophosphorous compounds"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:184,question:"A heterogeneous mixture can be defined as any mixture",option:{a:"Whose composition is uniform",b:"Whose composition is not uniform",c:"Formed by solids and liquids",d:"Of a solute and a solvent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:134,question:"Which of the following mixtures of gases is likely to burn in flame",option:{a:"Neon and hydrogen",b:"Nitrogen and helium",c:"Helium and neon",d:"Neon and nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:25,question:"3CU(s)  +  8HNO3(aq) →  3Cu(NO3)2(aq)  +  4H2O(I)  +  2NO(g)  In the equation above, copper is",option:{a:"An electron acceptor",b:"A base",c:"An oxidizing agent",d:"A reducing agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:199,question:"The enzyme responsible for converting sucrose into two simple isomeric sugars is",option:{a:"Invertase",b:"Amylase",c:"Lactose",d:"Maltase"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:136,question:"Pollution of underground water by metal ions is very likely in a soil that has high",option:{a:"Acidity",b:"Alkalinity",c:"Chloride content",d:"Nitrate content"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:121,question:"Which of the following is found in cotton",option:{a:"Starch",b:"Cellulose",c:"fat",d:"oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:55,question:"Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid burns the skin by",option:{a:"Heating",b:"Hydration",c:"Dehydration",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:5,question:"An oxide X02 has a vapour density of 32. What is the atomic mass of X [O = 16]",option:{a:"32",b:"20",c:"14",d:"12"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:192,question:"Sugar is separated from its impurities by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Evaporation",c:"Precipitation",d:"Crystallization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:279,question:"Which of the following salts is slightly soluble in water",option:{a:"CaSO4",b:"Na2CO3",c:"PbCl2",d:"AgCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:23,question:"C(s) + 2S (g)  → CS2 (g)      Δ H = +89kJ mol-1. The chemical equation above implies that",option:{a:"Each of carbon and sulphur has 89kJ of energy",b:"Both carbon and sulphur contribute 89kJ of energy",c:"89kJ of energy is released",d:"89kJ is absorbed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:159,question:"Sodium metal is always kept under oil because it",option:{a:"Readily reacts with water",b:"Is reduced by atmospheric nitrogen",c:"Reacts vigorously on exposure to air",d:"Reacts with oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:275,question:"Carbon (II) oxide is considered dangerous if inhaled mainly because it",option:{a:"Competes with oxygen in the blood",b:"Competes with carbon (IV) oxide in the blood",c:"Can cause lung cancer",d:"Can cause injury to the nervous system"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:285,question:"If a reaction is exothermic and thee is a great disorder, it means that",option:{a:"The reaction is in a state of equilibrium",b:"There will be a large increase in free energy",c:"There will be a large decrease in free energy",d:"The reaction is static"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:132,question:"The property of chlorine which causes hydrogen chloride to be more ionic than the chlorine molecule is its",option:{a:"Electrovalency",b:"Electron affinity",c:"Electropositivity",d:"Electronegativity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:193,question:"Equal moles of ethyne and hydrogen iodide react to give",option:{a:"CH2 = CH2",b:"CH2 = CHI",c:"CH2 – CHI",d:"CH2 – CI3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:12,question:"Pure solvents are obtained by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Condensation",c:"Extraction",d:"EvapopraTION"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:254,question:"The efficiency of a solid catalyst to increase reaction rates depends on its",option:{a:"Concentration",b:"Solubility",c:"Quantity",d:"Surface area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:247,question:"Water has the ability to dissolve almost all substances because its molecule has a structure with",option:{a:"One positive end and one neutral end",b:"Two positive ends",c:"One positive end and one negative end",d:"Two negative ends"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:122,question:"the principal constituent of natural gas is methane",option:{a:"ethane",b:"propane",c:"butane",d:"butane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:13,question:"What is the decrease in volume of air when pyrogallol is shaken with 30.00cm3 of air",option:{a:"15.00cm3",b:"6.00cm3",c:"0.63cm3",d:"0.06cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:238,question:"An example of aliphatic unsaturated hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"Butanol",b:"Propene",c:"Pentane",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:109,question:"The metal that liberates hydrogen from cold water in bubbles only is",option:{a:"Na",b:"K",c:"Ca",d:"Al"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:35,question:"A trihydric alkanol is",option:{a:"glycerol",b:"phenol",c:"glycol",d:"ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:190,question:"Which of these properties gives a solid its definite shape",option:{a:"Weak intermolecular attraction",b:"High boiling point",c:"High melting point",d:"Strong intermolecular attraction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:68,question:"A rock sample was added to cold dilute HNMO3. The gas evolved was passed into a solution of acidified K2Cr2O7 and the solution turned green. The rock sample contains",option:{a:"NO3-",b:"Cl-",c:"SO42-",d:"SO32-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:290,question:"A constituent common to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Tin",d:"Lead"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:88,question:"Which of the following ions is acidic",option:{a:"K+",b:"NO-3",c:"S2-",d:"H3O+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:267,question:"The stability of the noble gases is due to the fact that they",option:{a:"Have duplet or octet electron configurations",b:"Belong to group zero of the periodic table",c:"Are volatile in nature",d:"Have no electron in their outermost shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:161,question:"The alkyl group can be represented by the general formula",option:{a:"CnH2n+1",b:"CnH2n",c:"CnH2n+2",d:"CnH2n-2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:227,question:"The order in which a mixture of sand ammonium chloride and sodium chloride can be separated is",option:{a:"Sublimation   dissolution  filtration  evaporation",b:"Dissolution  dryness  filtration  evaporation",c:"Filtration  sublimation  evaporation  dryness",d:"Dissolution  filtration  sublimation  evaporation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:93,question:"When 10g of sodium hydroxide is dissolved in 1000cm3 of water, the solution formed is approximately   [Na = 23, H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.01 mol dm-3",b:"0.10 mol dm-3",c:"0.25 mol dm-3",d:"0.50 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:148,question:"Which of the following hydrogen halides has the highest entropy value",option:{a:"HF",b:"HCl",c:"HBr",d:"Hl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:153,question:"Which steam is passed over red-hot carbon, the substances produced are",option:{a:"Hydrogen and trioxocarbonate(IV) acid",b:"Hydrogen, oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Hydrogen and carbon (II) oxide",d:"Hydrogen and carbon (IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:21,question:"What current in amperes will deposit 2.7g of aluminium in 2 hours [Al = 27, f = 96500 C mol-1]",option:{a:"32",b:"8",c:"4",d:"16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:137,question:"A carcinogenic substance is",option:{a:"Asbestos dust",b:"Sawdust",c:"Nitrogen(II) oxide",d:"Carbon (II) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:219,question:"Zinc and carbon rods are used as anode and cathode respectively in a",option:{a:"Voltaic cell",b:"Lead accumulator",c:"Leclanche cell",d:"Daniel cell"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:77,question:"What is the percentage by mass of oxygen in Al2(SO4)3.2H2O",option:{a:"14.29%",b:"25.39%",c:"50.79%",d:"59.25%"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:57,question:"Three drops of a 1.0 mol dm-3 solution of Na OH are added to 20cm3 of a solution of pH8.4. the pH of the resulting solution will be",option:{a:"Greater than 8.4",b:"Unaltered",c:"Close to that of pure water",d:"Less than 8.4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:130,question:"An electron can be added to a halogen atom to form a halide ion with",option:{a:"2 valence electrons",b:"3 valence electrons",c:"7 valence electrons",d:"Valence electrons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:84,question:"A gas exerts pressure on its container because",option:{a:"Some of its molecules are moving faster than others",b:"Of the collision of the molecules with each other",c:"Of the mass of the molecules of gas",d:"The molecules of a gas collide with the walls of the container"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:151,question:"The allotrope of carbon used in the decolourization of sugar is",option:{a:"Graphite",b:"Soot",c:"Charcoal",d:"Lampblack"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:299,question:"The final products of the reaction between methane and chloride in the presence of ultraviolet light are hydrogen chloride and",option:{a:"Dichloromethane",b:"Tetrachloromethane",c:"Chloromethane",d:"Trichloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:214,question:"2H2 + O2  → 2H2O  ΔH = -571Kj  In equation above, how much heat will be liberated if 12.0g of hydrogen is burnt in excess oxygen?",option:{a:"-1713kJ",b:"+1142kJ",c:"-571kJ",d:"-1142kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:78,question:"The filter in a cigarette reduces the nicotine content by",option:{a:"Burning",b:"Adsorption",c:"Evaporation",d:"Absorption"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:172,question:"In a flame test for calcium, the flame appears",option:{a:"Blue when viewed through a blue glass",b:"Green when viewed through a blue glass",c:"Orange-red when viewed through a blue glass",d:"Brick-red when viewed through a blue glass"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:281,question:"The IUPAC nomencalatyre of the compound LiAIH4 is",option:{a:"Aluminium tetrahydrido lithium",b:"Tetrahydrido lithium aluminate (III)",c:"Lithium aluminium hydride",d:"Lithium tetrahydridoaluminate (III)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:167,question:` Alkanol + Alkanoic acid ⇌  Ester + water.
The reverse reaction of the equation above is known as
`,option:{a:"Hydrolysis",b:"Saponification",c:"Hydration",d:"Fermentation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:249,question:"One heating may be produced by shaking a detergent solution with",option:{a:"Cu(NO3)2",b:"AgNO3",c:"Ca(NO3)2",d:"NaNO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:185,question:"The density of a certain gas is 1.98g dm-3 at s.t.p. What is the molecular mass of the gas   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm-3]",option:{a:"26.0g",b:"31.0g",c:"54.0g",d:"44.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:303,question:" Two hydrocarbons X and Y were treated with bromine water. Decolorized the solution and Y did not. Which class of compound does Y belong",option:{a:"Alkynes",b:"Alkenes",c:"Alkanes",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:100,question:"In the electrolysis of a concentrated solution of sodium chloride using inert electrodes, which of the following ions are discharged at the cathode and anode respectively",option:{a:"Na+ and Cl-",b:"Na+ and OH-",c:"H+ and OH-",d:"H+ and Cl-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:125,question:"If a solution contains 4.8g of Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid. Calculate the amount of copper(II) oxide that will react with it  [CU = 64, O = 16, S = 32, H = 1]",option:{a:"0.8g",b:"4.0g",c:"40.0g",d:"80.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:300,question:"The correct order of increasing boiling points of the following  compounds C3H7OH, C7H16 and C4H10 is",option:{a:"C4H10  →  C7H16 → C3H7OH",b:"C7H16 → C3H7OH → C4H16",c:"C4H10  → C3H7OH  → C4H10",d:"C3H7OH →  C4H10  → C7H16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:201,question:"Kerosene is commonly used to remove the red colour stain of palm oil from clothes because it",option:{a:"Helps to spread the oil over a larger surface area",b:"Makes the oil evaporate easily by dissolving it",c:"Helps to dilute the oil and reduce its colour",d:"Reacts with the oil to form an odourless compound"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:64,question:"A gas X diffuses twice as fast as gas Y under the same conditions. If the relative molecular mass of X is 28. Calculate the relative molecular mass of Y",option:{a:"120",b:"14",c:"56",d:"112"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:6,question:"Milikan’s contribution to the development of atomic theory is the determination of",option:{a:"Charge on electron",b:"Positive rays",c:"Charge to amss ratio",d:"Cathode rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:252,question:"Carbon exists naturally in the combined state as",option:{a:"Diamond",b:"Coal",c:"Wood",d:"Graphite"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:226,question:"What is the mola. Mass of a substance, if 0.4 mole of the substance has a mass of 25.0g",option:{a:"6.3g",b:"40.0g",c:"62.5g",d:"2.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:298,question:"Which of the following is used to hasten the ripening of fruit",option:{a:"Ethanol",b:"Ethyne",c:"Ethane",d:"Ethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:126,question:"What volume of gas is evolved at s.t.p. if 2g of calcium trioxocarbonate(IV) is added to a solution of hydrochloric acid    [Ca = 40, C = 12, O = 16, CI = 35.5, H = 1, Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm3]",option:{a:"112cm3",b:"224cm3",c:"448cm3",d:"224cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:75,question:"What volume of oxygen is produced from the decomposition of 2 moles of KClO3 at s.t.p   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4 dm3]",option:{a:"22.4 dm3",b:"33.6 dm3",c:"44.8 dm3",d:"67.2 dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:118,question:"Ethanol reacts with excess acidified K2Cr2O7 to produce",option:{a:"Ethanoic acid",b:"Ethanol",c:"Ethyl ethanoate",d:"Ethanoic acid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:89,question:"The structural component that makes detergent dissolve more quickly in water than soap is",option:{a:"–SO3 –Na+",b:"–COO-Na+",c:"–SO4- Na+",d:"–COO-K+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:250,question:"Dynamic equilibrium describes a situation where",option:{a:"A reaction gives back the reactants",b:"Reactants are converted to products",c:"The concentration of reactants and products is equal",d:"Both forward and reverse reaction proceed at the same rate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:34,question:"Catalytic hydrogenation of benzene produces",option:{a:"Oil",b:"Cyclohexane",c:"Cycloexane",d:"Margarine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:241,question:"Nigerian crude oil is described as light crude because of its",option:{a:"Low aliphatic hydrocarbon content",b:"Low sulphur content",c:"High natural gas content",d:"High octane number"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:73,question:"The gas that gives brown colouration in brown ring test",option:{a:"Co2",b:"NO2",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:31,question:"The general formula for the alkanals is",option:{a:"ROH",b:"R2CO",c:"RCOOR1",d:"RCHO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:95,question:"If an equilibrium reaction has   H>0, the reaction will proceed favourably in the forward direction at",option:{a:"High temperature",b:"Any temperature",c:"Low temperature",d:"Minimum temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:27,question:"As the concentration of an electrolyte reduces, the conductivity",option:{a:"Reduces to zero",b:"Decreases",c:"Increases",d:"Is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:26,question:"When ΔH is negative, a reaction is said to be",option:{a:"Ionic",b:"Reversible",c:"Exothermic",d:"Endothermic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:174,question:"To obtain pure carbon(II) oxide from its mixture with carbon (IV)oxide, the mixture should be",option:{a:"Bubbled through concentrated Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid",b:"Bubbled through sodium hydroxide",c:"Passed over heated copper(II) oxide",d:"Bubbled through water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:269,question:"Elements in the same periodic table have the same",option:{a:"Atomic number",b:"Chemical properties",c:"Physical properties",d:"Number of shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:248,question:"An emulsion may be produced by shaking a detergent solution with",option:{a:"Palm wine",b:"Palm oil",c:"Ethanoic acid",d:"Water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:19,question:"A metal M displaces zinc from zinc chloride solution. This shows that",option:{a:"M is more electronegative than zinc",b:"Zinc is above hydrogen in the series",c:"M is more electropositive than zinc",d:"Electrons flow from zinc to M"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:146,question:"The mass of silver deposited when a current of 10A is passed through a solution of silver salt for 4830s is    [Ag = 108, F = 96500 Cmol-1]",option:{a:"108.0g",b:"54.0g",c:"27.0g",d:"13.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:131,question:"The shape of the s-orbital is",option:{a:"Spherical",b:"Elliptical",c:"Spiral",d:"Circular"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:115,question:"The leachate of a certain plant ash is used in local soap making because it contains",option:{a:"Sodium chloride and potassium hydroxide",b:"Sodium hydroxide",c:"Potassium hydroxide",d:"Soluble carbonates and hydrogen carbonates"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,o as subject,i as total};
